sugarspunrun.com 2019-07-22

# Policies, Disclosure & Privacy - Sugar Spun Run

Sugar Spun Run is a personal blog found at https://sugarspunrun.com / (“Website”) and is written and maintained by me, Samantha Merritt. This Website is governed by the following Privacy Policy.   Please contact me at Samantha@Sugarspunrun.com with any questions about this website.

### Affiliate Policy and Disclosures

SugarSpunRun.com accepts forms of cash advertising, sponsorship, paid insertions, or other forms of compensation. The compensation received will not influence the content found on this blog. Compensated content will be identified as paid or sponsored.

Some posts may occasionally contain affiliate links, which will be disclosed within the post.  This means that, if you purchase something through those links, I may receive some compensation at no extra cost to you.

All opinions shared on Sugar Spun Run are 100% my own, and are not influenced by any compensation that I might receive.  I will only promote products that I have used myself and truly love.

Sugar Spun Run is currently affiliated with Amazon.com, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to amazon.com. Amazon will track referrals to the site through the use of cookies. Please see [Amazon’s privacy policy](https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=footer_privacy?ie=UTF8&nodeId=468496) for more information.

### Copyright

© SugarSpunRun. All images and content are copyright protected. Unauthorized use and/or duplication of this material without express and written permission from this blog’s author and/or owner is strictly prohibited. Excerpts and links may be used, provided that full and clear credit is given with appropriate and specific direction to the original content.

If you are looking to get permission to use a photo from my site for a round-up, please feel free to do so as long as you clearly link back to the specific post that the image is from, and I ask that you do not alter the image.  Sharing the recipe along with the image is strictly prohibited.

If you would like to know more about using an image or excerpt from Sugar Spun Run, please feel free to contact me at sugarspunrunner@gmail.com with any questions.

###  **Privacy Policy for SugarSpunRun.com**

This privacy policy sets out how Sugar Spun Run uses and protects any information that you give while using SugarSpunRun.com. I am committed to protecting your privacy, the purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you of the personally identifiable information we may collect and how it may be used.

Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

SugarSpunRun  may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes.

###  **What Information Do We Collect and How is it Used?**

We may collect the following information:

 **Any information that you voluntarily submit to the website:**

  * We may collect personal information such as your name or email address. For example, you may voluntarily submit information to this website by leaving a comment, subscribing to the newsletter, or submitting a contact form.
  * Demographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests
  * Other information relevant to customer surveys and/or offers

 **Information We Collect from Others:**

  * We may receive information about you from other sources.

 **Information That is Collected Automatically:**

We automatically collect certain information about you and the device you are using to access the Website. For example, when you use the Website, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the Website. We may also collect information about actions you take when using the Website, such as links clicked.

 **Cookies:**

We may log information using cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by the Website. We may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the Website.

###  **How We Use the Information We Gather:**

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * We use this information to operate and maintain this Website.
  * We may use the information to improve our products and services.
  * To send you promotional information, such as newsletters. Each email promotion will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings.
  * To send you administrative communications, such as administrative emails, confirmation emails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts.
  * To respond to your comments or inquiries.
  * To track and measure advertising on the website.
  * To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity.
  * From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail. We may use the information to customize the website according to your interests.

### Third-Party Use of Personal Information

We may share your information with third parties when you explicitly authorize us to share this information.

Additionally, the Website may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies.

The Website currently uses the following third-party service providers:

 _Google Analytics_ – this service tracks Website usage and provides information such as referring websites and user actions on the Website. Google Analytics may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured by Google Analytics. Please see [Google Analytics Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) for more information.

 _Mail Chimp_ – This service is used for the delivery of email updates and newsletters. We store your name and email address for purpose of delivering such communications. Please refer to [Mail Chimp’s privacy policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) for further information.

 _One Signal_ – One Signal is used to send you notifications through your web browser, upon your agreement. You can find more information about One Signal’s privacy policies and practices at [One Signal](https://onesignal.com/privacy_policy).

 **Security**

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

 **How we use cookies**

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

###  **Advertising**

 **Display Ads**

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve content and advertisements when you visit the Website. Some of our advertisers occasionally serve you cookies as well. We do not have control over cookies placed by advertisers. We may use advertising service vendors to help present advertisements on the website, one of which is [http://www.mediavine.com](http://www.mediavine.com/). These vendors may use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies to serve you advertisements tailored to interests you have shown by browsing on this and other sites you have visited, to determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before and to avoid sending you duplicate advertisements. In doing so, these vendors may collect non-personal data such as your browser type, your operating system, Web pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, ads viewed, and other clickstream data. The use of cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies by these advertising service vendors is subject to their own privacy policies, not ours, and Service Provider disclaims all liability in connection therewith.

 **Retargeting Ads**

On occasion, the Website may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies such as Google, Facebook, or Instagram in order to market the Website. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visit to the Website.

 **Affiliate Program Participation**

This Website engages in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purpose of commissions.

Sugar Spun Run is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program and the RewardStyle affiliate advertising program, affiliate advertising programs designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon.com or other affiliate websites. As part of this Amazon Associates Program and RewardStyle, the Website will post customized links, provided by Amazon or RewardStyle, to track the referrals to their website. This program uses cookies to track visits for the purpose of assigning commission on these sales.

 **Newsletters**

You may subscribe to the Website’s newsletter, which may be used for advertising purposes and may contain tracking pixels. Tracking pixels are embedded in these emails and allow an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns. Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. This also allows the Website to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interest of the user. This behavior will not be passed on to third parties.

 **Links to other websites**

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

 **Controlling your personal information**

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:

  * whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes
  * if you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by contacting us.

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen. We may disclose or transfer personal information collected through the Website to third parties who acquire all or a portion of our business, which may be the result of a merger, consolidation, or purchase of all or a portion of our assets.

### Anonymous Data

We may on occasion use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies.

### Publicly Visible Information

If you leave a comment on the Website, certain information may be publicly visible. Your email address will never be available publicly. You may have the option to add an avatar, a profile description, and a link to your website. The name that you provide, your avatar, and your website information will be available if you leave a comment and include this information.

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please contact us.

### Rights Related to Your Personal Information

 **Opt-out** – You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may opt out of push  notifications by going to your device or browser “Settings” and clicking on “Notifications”. Here you can change your settings for receiving push notifications. Different device configurations may affect or change how these settings work.

Amend – You may contact us at Samantha@sugarspunrun.com to amend or update your personal information.

Forget – In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to Samantha@sugarspunrun.com

Access – You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to Samantha@sugarspunrun.com

Please be aware that we may need to retain certain information for record keeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

 **Sensitive Personal Information**

You should at no time submit any sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes information such as your social security number, any information regarding your race or ethnic origin, political opinions, health information, criminal background, religious beliefs, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

 **Children’s Information**

The Website does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at Samantha@sugarspunrun.com and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information for our records.

 **Contact Information**

Please contact us at any time at **Samantha@sugarspunrun.com** for any questions related to this Privacy Policy.

Privacy Policy last updated March 23, 2019
